Jessie Lloyd O'Connor Papers, 1850-1988
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE 1875-1988
  - Friends and associates
    - Pollard, Jennie O. [re: her sister, Louise Olivereau]1965 (Box 55, Folder 24)
      [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS -Articles and essays---Alphabetical by title-Revolution in Seattle]
    - Pope, Sally and Clifford1959-81, undated (Box 55, Folder 25)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne1937-54 (Box 55, Folder 26)
    - Price, Bill1945-71 (Box 55, Folder 27)
    - Prugh, Kitty and Tee1918-20 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - P1923-88, undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Q1955-62 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Rackliffe, Jack and Mary1952-66, undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Ransom, Thelma1948-61 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - [Redding], Helen [W.?]1923-24, undated (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Reeve, Carl and Ann1971-81, undated (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Reynolds, Malvina and Bud1952, 1962-77, undated (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Richt, Adrian and Hazel Reeve1925-30 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Riggs, Ione1976-81 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Robinson, Earl and Helen1941-82 (Box 56, Folder 11)
      [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS--Articles and essays-Alphabetical by subject-Robinson, Earl; and SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Earl Robinson Foundation]
    - Robinson, Geneva1955-57, undated (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Robinson, Hazel1965-81 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Rochester, Anna1932-49 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Rodzinska, Ilsa1967-77 (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Rogers, Lalla Rookh1931-73, undated (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Rogers, Robert Bruce1949-74, undated (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Rohm, Florence1935-88, undated (Box 57, Folder 1-4)
    - Rose, Rose1951-58, 1976 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Rossman, Harold1945-53, 1986 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Rubel, Dorothy L. (Box 57)
      [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Metropolitan Housing and Planning Council of Chicago]
    - Russell, Irene "Sasa"1920-58 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Russell, Margaret and Ralph1952-87, undated (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Russell, Maud1947-88, undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
      [SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Committee for a Democratic Far East Policy]
    - R1921-83, undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Sakamoto, Mae1943-58, undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Salt, Mary and Waldo1956-76, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Sanasen, George and Lous1956-76, undated (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Sanford, Helen and Marvin1962-73 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Sanger, Margaret1934-55 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Savary, Jacques and Sabine1952-85, undated (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Sawyer, Eunice1954-82, undated (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Saxton, Gertrude and Sandy1960-66 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Saxton, Mary "Mamie"1934-[44?] (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Schauffler, Leslie (Speel) and [Keenie?]1950-70 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Schindler, Pauline1954-74, undated (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Schlimmer, Doris1920-21 (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - Schoedler, Lillian1929?-1951, undated (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - Schonbrun, Sheila Jones1952-84, undated (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - Schroeder, Arthur and Norma1942-82, undated (Box 58, Folder 17)
    - Schulkind, Adelaide (Box 58)
      [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--The League for Mutual Aid]
    - Schwimmer, Franciska (includes Edith Wynner)1945-63, undated (Box 58, Folder 18-20)
      [see also Wynner, Edith]
    - Schwimmer, Rosika1925-48, undated (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Seeger, Pete and Toshi1942-88, undated, [see also Oversized Material] (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Seeman, Elizabeth and Ernest1941-87, undated (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Seibel, Jule1931-87, undated (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Serafini, Sula Wing and Enzo
      - 1936-49 (Box 59, Folder 5-6)
      - 1950-80, undated (Box 60, Folder 1-3)
    - Shaughnessy, Rae Booth1919-22, undated (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Shaw, Ethel1937-38 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Shaw, George Bernard1946 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Shaw, Herbert1937-39, 1950 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Shelley, Rebecca1956-69, undated (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Shelton, Henry and Carol1979-88, undated (Box 60, Folder 9)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--W.A.G.E.]
    - Sherer, Jo1963?-1974 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Shields, Art and Esther (includes two letters to Hays Jones)circa 1930-1967, undated (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Shipley, Miriam deFord1962-73 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Shubert, Katherine1974-78 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - Shufro, Ethel and Mike1952, 1964-83, undated (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - Simmons, Christina1976-85, undated (Box 61, Folder 1)
      [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL--Personal records- Papers]
    - Skau, Evelyn C.1966-68 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Smiljanic (Smilovic), George1951-53 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Smith, Gertrude P.circa 1947-84, undated (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Snow, Alice Rowe1949-55 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Soong, Ching-ling1928-80, undated (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Southworth, Evelina and Constant1963-74 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Spiegel, Sidney1919-20, undated (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Starbuck, Judy and Ward1953-86, undated (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Stavis, Esther and Morton1958-77, undated (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Stedman, Irene1945-55 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Steinberger, Charlotte1955-[63?], undated (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Steinhardt, Jacinto and Hazel1931-85 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - Steinmetz, Harry and Doris1958-83 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Stevenson, Janet and Philip1951, 1953, 1965-79, undated (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - Stevenson, Maryan1949-78 (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - St. John, Jim and Nancy1942-57 (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - Stiles, W.K.1930-31 (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - Stokes, Helen Hamilton1948-88, undated (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - Stone, I.F. (Box 61)
      [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-I.F. Stone's Weekly]
    - Strasmich, Dotty and Irving1958-63 (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - Straus, Nancy1940, 1963-83, undated (Box 61, Folder 21)
    - Straus, Albert, Betsy, and Francis1957, 1965?, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - Strauss, Sonia (Box 61)
      [see Gruen, Sonia Strauss and Kurt]
    - Strawn, Betty Rogers1920-69 (includes letters from Baird and J.G. Rogers) (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - Strong, Anna Louise1931-34, 1948-66, undated (Box 61, Folder 24)
      [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS-Articles and essays-Alphabetical by subject-Russia-Moscow Daily News]
    - Studnicka, Anne1942, 1958-67 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Sumners, Polly Houghton1951-52, 1980, undated (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Sun Yat-sen, Madame (Box 62)
      [see Soong, Ching-ling]
    - Sward, Keith and Ruth1936-88, undated (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Sweezy, Nancy1958-59, undated (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Syjatz, Lydia1972, 1975 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - S1929-88, undated (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Taylor, John1950-55 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Teller, Julia and Sidney1942-65, undated (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Thalinger, Ciel, Ernest, and Jean1942-88, undated (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Thomas, Caroline Bedell1922-88, undated (Box 62, Folder 10-12)
    - Thomas, Elizabeth and Peggy1950-83, undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Thomas, Gwen1951-53 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Thurston, Connie1951-56, 1973, [1981?] (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Timpson, Anne Burlak1963-78, undated (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Todd, Alden and Jean[1951?]-1988, undated (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Tolstoy, Alexandra and Olga1927-31, 1978? (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Tramell, Mildred1947-48 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Trebes, Rose1920-24, [1944]-63 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Twadell, Helen Johnson1949-85, undated (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - T1932-87, undated (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Underwood, Sherry1965-70 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Uphaus, Ola and Willard1952-78 (Box 63, Folder 12)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Willard Uphaus Committee and World Fellowship, Inc.]
    - U1955-66, undated (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Van Fliess, Norah1968-82, undated (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Van Orden, Katharinecirca 1953-55 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Van Voris, Jacqueline (Box 63)
      [see SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL--Smith College--Centennial Study]
    - Veenis, Y.[evebaud?]1940-68 (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Vild, Bruce1979-88 (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Vincent, Jenny and Craig1949-89, undated (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - Vorse, Mary Heaton1937-circa 1963, undated (Box 63, Folder 19)
    - V1936-88, undated (Box 63, Folder 20)
    - Warburg, Wilma Shannon1937-85, undated (Box 63, Folder 21)
    - Warner, Nan1940-43, undated (Box 63, Folder 22)
    - Warren, Bill1985-88 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Warren, Kay[1923?]-24, [1950?], 1969-87, undated (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Warrior, Audrey1956-57 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Watson, Rowdy1948-60, undated (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Watt, Carl and Elizabeth1961-84 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Weisberg, Rose1950-55, 1979 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Weld, Wallace1970 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Wertheim, Violacirca 1940s-1959, undated (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - West, Ann1981-82 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - West, Don1949-87, undated (Box 64, Folder 10)
      [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES--Appalachia, and West, Don and Hedy]
    - West, Dorothy Bucklin1967-88, undated (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Wetter, Gladys and Pierce1932, 1951-57 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - White, Ruth and William1947-58, 1975, 1978, undated (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Whyte, Harry1934 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Wilkinson, Jean, Frank, and Donna1957-88 (Box 64, Folder 15)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--National Committee Against Repressive Legislation/National Committee to Abolish the House Un-American Activities Committee]
    - Willcox, Anita Parkhurst and Henry1958-78 (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - Williams, Claude and Joyce1942-78, undated (Box 64, Folder 17-18)
    - Williams, Constance1940-88, undated (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - Williams, Lucita, Rhys, and Eleanorcirca 1930s-81, undated (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - Wilson, Peggy Windes and Herb1920-88, undated (Box 65, Folder 1-3)
    - Windes, Guilford R.1955-82, undated (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Winn, David1960-[87?], undated (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Winsor, Mary1942-48 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Winstead, Olga (Box 65, Folder 7)
      [see Peters, Olga Winstead]
    - Winstead, Ralph and Zena1935-59, undated (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Winterburne, Florence, Hull1937-43, undated (Box 65, Folder 9)
      [see also Subjects-Charity for individuals]
    - Wislocki, Florence (Fliss)1956, 1973-79, undated (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Withington, Dorothea1966, 1983-87, undated (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Withington, Margaret (Chips), Paul, and Lucy1946-80, undated (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Wohl, Harry and Esther1945-82, undated (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - Woodhouse, Betts1955-76 (Box 65, Folder 14)
    - Woodward, Marshall M.1953-54, 1979, 1987, undated (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - Wordell, Marie and Herbert1978-86, undated (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - Wortley, Eloise and Kay1921-25 (Box 65, Folder 17)
    - Wright, Dave1962-85 (Box 65, Folder 18)
    - Wright, Katharine Beecher ("Beechie")1943-64, undated (Box 65, Folder 19)
    - Wright, Lucy1955?-69 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Wynner, Edith
      [see also Schwimmer, Franciska]
      - 1930-61 (Box 66, Folder 2-8)
      - 1962-87, undated (Box 67, Folder 1-6)
    - Wysong, May (Box 67)
      [see Parkhurst, Minnie and May Wysong]
    - W1927-88, undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Yeomans, Andy and Betty1947-66, undated (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Yeomans, Julia1943-60, undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Yohalem, Mary1970-83, undated (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Young, Art1929, 1937-40 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Zipf, Herbert Lloyd and Collette Anderson1919-25, 1948-62, undated (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Y-Z1935-83, undated (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified
      - 1910-39 (Box 68, Folder 8-14)
      - 1940-79 (Box 69, Folder 1-21)
      - 1980-88, undated (Box 70, Folder 1-9)
      - Drafts of love letters/notes1940-41, undated (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - O'Connor's annual/Christmas letters1945-88 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Third party (friends and associates to others) (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - General/business
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1910-35 (Box 70, Folder 13-15)
      - 1936-53 (Box 71, Folder 1-10)
      - 1954-71 (Box 72, Folder 1-18)
      - 1972-88, undated (Box 73, Folder 1-12)
    - Architects and contractors1947-51, undated (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Archives and libraries
      - Archives of Labor and Urban Affairs, Wayne State University (Harvey O'Connor Papers)1968-88 (Box 73, Folder 14)
      - Labadie Collection, University of Michigan (Agnes Inglis) 1940-42 (Box 73, Folder 15)
      - New York Public Library (Lloyd family papers)circa 1943-84, undated (Box 73, Folder 16)
        [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES -Schwimmer-Lloyd Collection]
      - Sophia Smith Collection (Jessie Lloyd O'Connor Papers)1978-86, undated (Box 74, Folder 1)
        [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE-Grierson, Margaret]
      - State Historical Society of Wisconsin (Henry Demarest Lloyd Papers)1949-83, undated (Box 74, Folder 2)
      - University of Washington Libraries1962-72 (Box 74, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous1942-86, undated (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Charity for individuals
      - Anderson, Jennie1949-63, undated (Box 74, Folder 5)
      - Vacarelli, Alta1947, undated (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - Winterburne, Florence1940-43 (Box 74, Folder 7)
        [see also Friends and associates-Winterburne, Florence]
    - Children
      - Adoption, miscellaneous1937-45 (Box 74, Folder 8)
      - Chicago Foundlings Home (re: Kathleen O'Connor)1945-53 (Box 74, Folder 9)
      - Child Placing and Adoption Committee, State Charities Aid Association (New York City)1939-42 (Box 74, Folder 10)
      - Bernard, Dr. Viola1939-63 [restricted] (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - Physicians, dentists, etc.
        - Feigen, Simeon (re: Kathleen O'Connor)1963-69 [restricted] (Box 75, Folder 2)
        - Miscellaneous1948-68, undated [restricted] (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - Schools and camps
        - Boston University (Stephen O'Connor)1959, 1967 (Box 75, Folder 4)
        - Cambridge School of Weston (re: Kathleen O'Connor)1953-59, undated (Box 75, Folder 5)
        - Friends Academy (North Dartmouth, MA)1949-57, undated (Box 75, Folder 6)
        - Kinhaven1954-83, undated (Box 75, Folder 7)
          [see also Friends and associates--Dushkin, Dorothy Smith, David, and Lelah]
        - Lincoln Farm Work Camp1955-57 (Box 75, Folder 8)
        - Oakwood School1956-57, undated (Box 75, Folder 9)
        - Timberline, An Interracial Camp for Boys and Girls1955, undated (Box 75, Folder 10)
        - Windsor Mountain School (Lenox, MA)1954-70, undated (Box 75, Folder 11)
        - Miscellaneous 1948-58, undated (Box 75, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous1945-69 (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Globus Trading Corporation1949-62 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Health, nutrition, physicians, etc.1932-88, undated (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Hired help1932-72, undated (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - James T. White and Co., Publishers1945-47 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Public
      [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS-Articles and essays-Alphabetical by subject--letters to the editor, for published letters to the editor]
      - 1930-54 (Box 76, Folder 5-9)
      - 1955-84 (Box 77, Folder 1-6)
      - 1985-88, undated (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Red Gold Groves (Harry and Marjorie Riddle)1945-69 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Soviet Embassy and New York Consulate1938-45 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Transcriptions of selected correspondence with family and friends
    - 1903-24 (Box 78, Folder 4-7)
    - 1925-32 (Box 79, Folder 1-8)
    - 1933-40 (Box 80, Folder 1-9)
    - 1941-44 (Box 81, Folder 1-10)
    - 1945-49, undated (Box 82, Folder 1-8)
- SERIES III. WRITINGS 1889-1989
  - Diaries and appointment calendars
    [see also oversize material for 1985-88]
    - 1916, 1917 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - 1919, 1921, 1923 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - 1925-27 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - 1928-29, 1938?, 1942 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - 1944-45 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - 1947, 1949 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - 1952-56, 1958 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - 1960-62 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - 1963, 1966 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - 1971, 1976-79, 1981 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Fragments (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Notebooks1920s-60s, undated (Box 85, Folder 3-5)
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous1929-88 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Re: Lexikon der Fraucirca 1956 (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Articles and essays
    - Alphabetical by title
      - "Civil Liberties: the American Way" undated (Box 85, Folder 8)
      - "Don't Look Now, But Have You Noticed How Crazy the World Is Getting?" 1964 (Box 85, Folder 9)
      - "Eternal Vigilance the Price of Liberty" 1945 (Box 85, Folder 10)
      - "Food and Health" undated (Box 85, Folder 11)
      - "Freeze and Thaw" undated (Box 85, Folder 12)
      - "Genesis of the Smith Act" undated (Box 85, Folder 13)
      - "Give 'em Air" circa 1938 (Box 85, Folder 14)
      - "A Housewife Looks at International Affairs," circa 1961: correspondence and drafts1961, undated (Box 85, Folder 15)
      - "The Hungary That Was When Hungary Was Liberal: A Tale of Four Cities" undated (Box 85, Folder 16)
      - "Intolerable, Gentleman!/A Manufacturer's Nightmare" undated (Box 85, Folder 17)
      - "Iran: Big Oil and the Hostages" 1981 (Box 86, Folder 1)
      - "Is Ireland 'Settled'? Interview with Eamon de Valera" 1926: correspondence, drafts, notes, and research material (Box 86, Folder 2)
      - "Kurt/Fritz Becomes a Furore" circa 1939: correspondence and drafts (Box 86, Folder 3)
      - "A Monkey Looks at Economics" undated (Box 86, Folder 4)
      - "Mushrooms" undated (Box 86, Folder 5)
      - "Neighborhood Chairman" 1939: correspondence and draft (Box 86, Folder 6)
      - "Nothing to Fear but Fear" undated (Box 86, Folder 7)
      - "On the Unreasonableness of Woman" 1940-42 (Box 86, Folder 8)
      - "One Woman's Rebellion" circa 1945: correspondence and drafts (Box 86, Folder 9)
      - "Our Teeth: What's the Matter with Them?," 1936: correspondence, drafts, and research material1936-43 (Box 86, Folder 10)
      - "Patriotism: False and True" 1951-54 (Box 86, Folder 11)
      - "Patriotism (Thoughts By One Who Has Had Friends on the Right and on the Left)" 1951 (Box 86, Folder 12)
      - "Pax Americana" 1965 (Box 86, Folder 13)
      - "A Personal Appeal in a Crisis" 1940: correspondence, drafts, and notes re: conscription (Box 86, Folder 14)
      - "Personal Tragedy/Chapter 28" circa 1958 (Box 86, Folder 15)
      - "Preparedness or National Defense? We Can't Have Both" undated (Box 86, Folder 16)
      - "Prerequisite" undated (Box 86, Folder 17)
      - Revolution in Seattle by Harvey O'Connor (1964), chapter on Louise Olivereau by Jessie Lloyd O'Connor: correspondence, drafts, notes, and research material1961-63 (Box 86, Folder 18)
        [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--Friends and associates-- Pollard, Jennie O.]
      - "Simplified Spelling?" undated (Box 86, Folder 19)
      - "So This Is America?," People's Press16 Jan 1937: published article and drafts (Box 86, Folder 20)
      - "Statement of Membership in Organizations and Activities" undated (Box 86, Folder 21)
      - "Statement to the Democratic National Committee Men of Rhode IslandJune 30, 1960" (Box 86, Folder 22)
      - "The Story of the Peace Ship," 27 Dec 1965; "What Did the Peace Ship Accomplish in 1916?," 28 Dec 1965, Providence Journal: published articles, drafts, correspondence re: Peace Ship, notes and research materials (includes reminiscences from Jessie, Mary Maverick Lloyd, and William Bross Lloyd, Jr., n.d.), 1949-67 (Box 86, Folder 23)
        [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE-Friends and associates- Fussell, Paul]
      - "Thoughts by Jessie Lloyd O'Connor" undated (Box 86, Folder 24)
      - "Three Feet of Earth or Now and Then?" 1960s (Box 86, Folder 25)
      - Tragedy of Russia by Will Durant, book reviewundated (Box 86, Folder 26)
      - "Two Americans Look at Russia, The Nation13 Mar 1929 (book review of Dreiser Looks at Russia by Theodore Dreiser and The Hammer and the Scythe by Anne O'Hare McCormick): published review and correspondence (Box 86, Folder 27)
      - What Next? A Bad Word, a Good Deal, Freedom, too (self-published pamphlet on socialism), 1977: pamphlet, drafts, notes, and correspondence1975-80 (Box 86, Folder 28)
      - "What's Practical? Acceptable? War?," World Peace NewsApr 1978: published article and drafts (Box 87, Folder 1)
      - "Who's the Villain-Human Nature or National Sovereignty," World Federation-NowDec 1945 (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - "Why the Soviets Want to Get to the Moon: And Why Uncle Sam Can't Let Them!" 1962 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Alphabetical by subject
      - Autobiographical1952, 1970, 1978, undated (Box 87, Folder 4)
      - CIO Councilor article re: San Francisco conference, fragmentsundated (Box 87, Folder 5)
      - Climax Molybdenum Mine, Climax, CO: correspondence, notes, and research materialscirca 1936 (Box 87, Folder 6)
      - Communismundated (Box 87, Folder 7)
      - Cuba: article re: attacks on Cuban womencirca 1931: notes and drafts (Box 87, Folder 8)
      - Friends and family: notes, poems, plays, and eulogies1950-86, undated (Box 87, Folder 9)
      - Haymarket, Chicagoundated (Box 87, Folder 10)
      - Humor1929, 1938, undated (Box 87, Folder 11)
      - Interviews by JLO1953, 1973, undated (Box 87, Folder 12)
      - Labor: radio script (dialogue with "Mr. Zeldow")1937 (Box 87, Folder 13)
      - Letters to the editor, published1935-84, undated (Box 87, Folder 14)
        [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE-General/business-- Public, for letters that were never published, or publication couldn't be determined]
      - Lloyd, Henry Demarest: notes and fragmentsundated (Box 87, Folder 15)
      - McCarthy, Joseph: drafts and notes (includes statements re: revocation of JLO's passport and a fragment re: Harvey O'Connor's speaking tour)1954-57, undated (Box 87, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous typescripts and fragments1947-84?, undated (Box 87, Folder 17)
      - Music and dance: drafts and published versions, correspondence, and contract
        - 1934-82, undated (Box 87, Folder 18-19)
        - Audiotape of JLO singing "Why'n'cha" (Box 88, Folder 1)
        - Sailor songsundated (Box 88, Folder 2)
      - Poetry1925-87, undated (Box 88, Folder 3)
      - Polish workers, Chicago: drafts, correspondence, research materials, and notes1939 (Box 88, Folder 4-5)
      - Recipes1920-73, undated (Box 88, Folder 6)
      - Robinson, Earl1944, 1961, undated (Box 88, Folder 7)
        [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE -Robinson, Earl and Helen; SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-Earl Robinson Foundation]
      - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel1953 (Box 88, Folder 8)
        [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES -Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel]
      - Russia
        - Book (A Flapper Goes to Russia/The Truth about Polly in Russia)
          - Correspondence re: manuscripts1929, 1931 (Box 88, Folder 9)
          - Draftscirca 1928-29
            - A Flapper Goes to Russia
              - Copy 1 (Box 88, Folder 10-15)
              - Copy 2 (Box 89, Folder 1-5)
            - The Truth about Polly in Russia, 2 copies (Box 89, Folder 6-11)
            - Draft fragmentscirca 1928-29 (Box 90, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence
          - General and Moscow Daily News1928-38 (Box 90, Folder 2)
          - Re: Russian Digest1945, undated (Box 90, Folder 3)
        - Diary and travel notes1927-28 (Box 90, Folder 4-6)
        - JLO reading 1927-28 diary (3 audiotapes) (Box 90, Folder 7)
        - Freelance articles: published versions, drafts, and fragments1927-35, undated (Box 90, Folder 8-9)
        - "Russian Dispatches Taken from New York TimesJuly-Sept., 1928" (by JLO and others) (Box 91, Folder 1)
        - Notebooksundated (Box 91, Folder 2)
        - Notes1927-28, undated (Box 91, Folder 3-5)
        - Printed (research?) material (mostly in Russian) (Box 91, Folder 6)